SEAN MCDONNELL

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

CONTACT

(267) 772-4490

✓ mcdsean@gmail.com

⇔ sean-mcdonnell.com

spmcdonnell

in mcdonnell-sean

DEVELOPS IN

FRONT END

- HTML React
- CSSRedux
- JavaScript

BACK END

- Node JS MYSQL
- Laravel
 Postgres
- PHP Python

TOOLS

- Photoshop
 webpack
- VS Code
 Illustrator

INTERESTS

- BMX
- Language Learning
- Gymnastics
- Sewing/textile arts
- Virtual Reality
- Fitness
- Video games
- Surfing
- Hiking

PROFILE

Ambitious college graduate with extensive experience living, studying, and working abroad. Wide ranging software development experience from conception to design, coding, deployment, and maintenance. Strong ability to adapt to new situations and work effectively with others. Articulate, organized, self-motivated, and highly detail oriented with a strong passion for acquiring knowledge and developing new skills.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

WEB DEVELOPER

Ink-it Digital | Philadelphia, PA | November 2015 - Present

- Build and maintain websites using a variety of front and back end technologies with a focus on developing new brands and building startups into successful companies.
- Provide on-site and remote training sessions and ongoing 1-on-1 support for clients.
- Create and maintain email/search engine advertisement campaigns and manage client social media accounts to drive site traffic.
- Collaborate with design and marketing teams to establish brand identity and tailor website UI/UX for anticipated user base.

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

Philadelphia, PA | 2015

- Utilized a variety of WordPress themes and custom code to create attractive and responsive websites including blog, local business, and e-commerce sites.
- Provided training and ongoing site maintenance for clients.

ENGLISH TEACHER / TRANSLATOR

Tokyo, Japan | 2013 - 2014

- Developed creative and engaging lesson plans based on middle school English curriculum.
- Utilized technology and linked lesson content with popular media and student's interests.
- Widened potential customer-base of clients by providing accurate and thorough Japanese to English document translation across a variety of subject matter.

PROJECTS

EDUCATIONWORKS

www.educationworks.org

- Worked to redesign and refine the user experience of this non-profit website. Successfully improved traffic and SEO through fewer, but more feature rich pages.
- Improved client's ability to maintain their site through heavy custom field customization.

POWERCORPS

www.powercorpsphl.org

- Created an attractive, functional and intuitive website to modernize the web presence of the local Philadelphia chapter of AmeriCorps.
- Increased charitable donations through improved SEO and ample callout sections.

RED CARPET INN

www.redcarpetinnnj.com

- Increased sales by creating a performant and easy to use website that streamlines the reservation process and keeps potential guests apprised of everything they need to know.
- React front end and Node/Postgres backend combined to create feature rich experience that allows users to plan and organize trips to nearby locations.

EDUCATION

TEMPLE UNIVERSITY JAPAN CAMPUS | 2007 - 2010

Bachelor of Arts, Major in Asian Studies, Minor in Japanese | Tokyo, Japan

MIDDLEBURY JAPANESE LANGUAGE SCHOOL | 2010

Middlebury, Vermont

INTER-UNIVERSITY CENTER FOR JAPANESE STUDIES | 2012-2013

Yokohama, Japan